Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Bird's-Eye Views, 1860-1959; Series VI; 1.67; (1 box)
  - OREGON
    - Portland
      - Brown, Grafton T. "City of Portland, Oregon 1865." Offset lithograph, 53.5 x 73.5 cm.
        "Presented to Members of the Lang Syne Society with the compliments of Norris, Beggs & Simpson"
      - Kuchel & Dresel. "Portland, Multnomah County, Oregon 1858." Offset lithograph, 44 x 69.7 cm., 1938
        Reproduction by James, Kerns & Abbott Company of Portland for the Lang Syne Society
      - Mutual L. & L. Co. "Birds Eye View of Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition and Oriental Fair, Portland, Oregon." Chromolithograph, 69.5 x 114.5 cm. in frame 100.5 x 145.5 cm.
        With souvenir ticket dated Sep 30 1905, no. 1274 pasted in lower left corner
      - Mutual L. & L. Co. "Birds Eye View of Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition and Oriental Fair, Portland, Oregon." Chromolithograph, 71.1 x 116.5 cm.
        Stamped in red ink at top with logo of Northern Pacific R.R. Yellowstone Park Line and text "Low Excursion Rates via Northern Pacific. For Particulars in Regard to Excursions Ask N. P. Ry. Agt."
      - Unidentified. "Portland, Oregon. Metropolis of the Pacific Northwest." Chromolithograph
        "Schmidt Label & Lith."
    - Salem
      - Kuchel & Dresel. "Salem, Marion County, Oregon. 1858." Colored lithograph, visible image 50 x 67.5 cm.
        Published by W.C. Griswold & Co.
  - WASHINGTON
    - Aberdeen
      - "Bird's Eye View of Aberdeen. Gray's Harbor, Wash. 1900." Chromolithograph, 61 x 96.5 cm.
        "Lith. Payot, Upham & Co., S.F." Manuscript notation on print with "your lot" marked in margin
      - "Bird's Eye View of Aberdeen, Wash." Collotype folding postcard, 9 x 27.8 cm.
    - Fairhaven
      - Unidentified. "Fairhaven: A Bird's-Eye View of the City and Harbor." Lithograph, 39.6 x 53.5 cm. (Box 52, Folder 1022)
        From The Graphic
      - Unidentified. "Fairhaven, Washington, 1891." Tinted lithograph, 71 x 107 cm., n.d.
        "Presented by the Fairhaven Land Co. Published by Elliott Pub. Co."
    - Goldendale
      - Unidentified. [Goldendale, Washington Territory.] Lithograph, 49.1 x 64.5 cm., 1886
        "Compliments of Goldendale Sentinel"
    - Gray's Harbor
      - Winsor, [----?]. [View of Gray's Harbor.] Pictorial lettersheet for Hoquiam Land Co., Hoquiam and Grays Harbor Real Estate, 22.3 x 29.9 cm. (Box 52, Folder 1023)
        Image of Hoquiam Land Company at top and view of Gray's Harbor on verso
      - Unidentified. "Bird's Eye View of Gray's Harbor Country, Chehalis Co., Washington." Color print, 34.5 x 46.5 cm. (Box 52, Folder 1024)
        "Tacoma Engraving Co. Per Brown"
    - Olympia
      - Glover, E. S. "Bird's Eye View of the City of Olympia, East Olympia and Tumwater, Puget Sound, Washington Territory, 1879." Tinted lithograph, 51 x 80 cm.
        "A.L. Bancroft & Co., Lithographers, San Francisco"
        Stored in: Broadside folder 1226
    - Seattle
      Glover, E. S. "Bird's-Eye View of the City of Seattle, Puget Sound, Washington Territory, 1878." Tinted lithograph, visible image 52.6 x 84.4 cm.
      Stored in: Broadside folder 1227
      - Caughey, Rollin B. "Authorized Bird's Eye View of the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, Seattle, U.S.A., 1909. Opens June 1st closes Oct. 16th." Chromolithograph, 63 x 100 cm. in frame 82.5 x 119.5 cm.
        "Schmidt Litho Co., Seattle"
      - Unidentified. "Seattle, 1889." Tinted lithograph, 60 x 95 cm., 1946
        Reprinted by Seattle Historical Society
    - Tacoma
      - Glover, E. S. "View of New Tacoma and Mount Rainier, Puget Sound, Washington Territory. Terminus of the Northern Pacific Railroad." Tinted lithograph, 48.5 x 74 cm., 1878
        "A.L. Bancroft & Co., Lith."
      - Wellge, H. "View of the City of Tacoma, W.T. Puget-Sound, County Seat of Pierce Cty. Pacific Terminus of the N.P.R.R. 1884." Lithograph, 45.8 x 90.5 cm.
        "Beck & Pauli, Lith. Published by J. J. Stoner"
      - Unidentified. "Tacoma 1889." Lithograph, 61 x 95.5 cm.
        "Published by Geo. W. Traver, Tacoma, Washington"
      - Carson, Will. "Tacoma, Western Terminus of the Northern Pacific Railroad." Chromolithograph, 78.5 x 110.5 cm., 1890
        Stored in: Broadside folder 1231
    - Vancouver
      - Unidentified. "Vancouver, Wash. 1889." Lithograph, 47.3 x 61 cm., n.d.
        "Compliments of Elwell Bros., Real Estate Brokers. Elliott Litho. Co."
- Maps, 1851-1890; Series VII; 1.67; (1 box)
  Series VII, Maps, is organized into two subseries: Oregon and Washington. Within each subseries the maps are organized chronologically.
  - OREGON
    - Hallock, A. B. "Map of Portland." Pen-and-ink and wash map, 49.5 x 60 cm., 1855
    - Preston, John B. "A Diagram of a Portion of Oregon Territory." Lithograph, 94.5 x 40 cm., 1851
    - Surveyor General's Office. "Oregon." Lithograph, colored, 47.3 x 58.5 cm., 1866 (Box 53, Folder 1025)
      "The Major & Knapp Eng. Mfg. & Lith. Co., N.Y."
    - Burrage, C. W. "Map of the City of Portland." Lithograph, 33 x 41 cm., 1867 (Box 53, Folder 1026)
      "Britton & Rey, Liths. San Francisco. Published by S. J. McCormick." With ms. annotation indicating 5th Street
    - W.B. Obenauer & Co. "Map of Marion County Oregon." Lithograph, 61 x 61 cm., n.d.
      "Published expressly for Wm. G. Obenauer & Co's. Directory of Salem and Marion Co. Lewis & Dryden Lith. Co., Portland, Or."
      Stored in: Oversize box 63, folder 1189
    - Unidentified. "Ethnographical Map of Oregon from Hales Ethnology of the Amer. Exploring Expedition." Lithograph, 22.6 x 29.8 cm., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1027)
      "Lith of Wm. Endicott & Co. N. York." From volume 6 of United States Exploring Expedition. During the years 1838, 1839, 1840, 1841, 1842. Under the command of Charles Wilkes. Philadelphia, Lea & Blanchard, 1845-1874.
  - WASHINGTON
    - Unidentified. "Map of Vancouver Island and Washington Territory, showing San Juan Island and the Disputed Territory." Engraving, 20.5 x 26.4 cm., 1859 Oct (Box 53, Folder 1028)
      Part of an unidentified serial, dated Oct 1859 in pencil at bottom
    - Morgan, Edward A. "Map of Puget Sound, Washington Territory." Rolled wall map, colored lithograph, 133 x 101.5 cm., 1875
      Britton, Rey & Co. Lith, San Francisco
    - Levy, Lewis. "Town of Port Angeles, Washington with Additions." Lithograph, 35.4 x 61 cm., 1890 (Box 53, Folder 1029)
      "Compiled by Lewis Levy, Real Estate Broker, Port Angeles, Wash."
    - Decourcy, B. W. "Map of Dundee Place. The Supplementary Addition to the Hastings Third Addition to Port Townsend, Wash." Chromolithograph, 48.5 x 63.4 cm.
      "Lewis & Dryden Map Engs. Portland Or."
- Other Manuscripts and Papers, 1676-1915; Series VIII; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series VIII, Other Manuscripts and Papers, is organized into two subseries: Manuscripts and Ephemera and Photographs. The Manuscripts and Ephemera are organized by George Andrews Family Correspondence, John McLoughlin Papers, Dover/Smith Papers, Thomas Smith Documents, Valentine Smith Family Correspondence, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Miscellaneous Documents, Miscellaneous Writings, Miscellaneous Printed Material, and Other Material. The Photographs are organized by Western photographs and Other photographs.
  - MANUSCRIPTS AND EPHEMERA
    - George Andrews Family Correspondence
      - Andrews, George, Boston to William Neil, Portsmouth (Box 54, Folder 1030)
      - Andrews, John, Modbury, England to uncle George Andrews, Dover, New Hampshire, 1846 Dec 26 (Box 54, Folder 1031)
      - Crawford, J. J., Court Dittisham, England to brother George Crawford, care of George Andrews, Dover, near Portsmouth, 1801 Nov 8 (Box 54, Folder 1032)
      - Evans, William H., West Union to uncle George Andrews, Dover, New Hampshire, 1848 Jan 19 (Box 54, Folder 1033)
      - Evans, William H., West Union to uncle George Andrews, Dover, New Hampshire, 1848 Jun 27 (Box 54, Folder 1034)
    - John McLoughlin Papers
      - Document signed by John McLoughlin, 1850 Sep 16 (Box 54, Folder 1035)
      - Crow and Lussier. Two card photographs of Dr. John McLoughlin, 14 x 9.3 cm. on mount 16.2 x 10.7 cm. (Box 54, Folder 1036)
        "Compliments of Margaret G. Wygant." Crow and Lussier, Portland Oregon
    - Dover/Smith Papers
      - Deed of land from John York of Dover to Michael French of Dover. "Veria copia from ye Original", 1676 Jun 28 (Box 54, Folder 1037)
      - Smith, Joseph, of Dover. Deed of land from Robert Smart, Sr., 1706 Apr 8 (Box 54, Folder 1038)
      - Smith, John, of Dover. Deed of land from John Rawlins, 1717 Mar 22 (Box 54, Folder 1039)
      - Smith, John, Jr., Captain. Company roll of the soldiers on "the south side of Oyster River, Dover", 1732 (Box 54, Folder 1040)
    - Thomas Smith Documents
      - Pierce, Franklin. Temporary appointment of Thomas M. Smith as Auditor of the Treasury. Document signed, 1856 Jan 8 (Box 54, Folder 1041)
      - Buchanan, James. Temporary appointments of Thomas M. Smith as Auditor of the Treasury. Two documents signed, 1859 Mar (Box 54, Folder 1042)
      - Lincoln, Abraham. Temporary appointment of T. M. Smith as Auditor of the Treasury. Document signed, 1865 Feb 3 (Box 54, Folder 1043)
    - Valentine Smith Family Correspondence
      - Emerson, William, Bangor to Valentine Smith, Durham, New Hampshire, 1848 Apr 14 (Box 54, Folder 1044)
      - Emerson, William, Bangor to Valentine Smith, Durham, New Hampshire, 1848 May 26 (Box 54, Folder 1045)
      - Smith, Thomas, New York to Valentine Smith, Durham, New Hampshire, 1838 Aug 8 (Box 54, Folder 1046)
      - Smith, Valentine, Louisville to John Edwards Smith care of V. Smith, Durham, New Hampshire, 1838 May 28 (Box 54, Folder 1047)
        Discusses slavery in Kentucky
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence
      - Bingham, [H.?] P. Postcard to Mrs. Gen. I. I. Stevens, 1909 Jul 12 (Box 54, Folder 1048)
      - Ripley, Joseph, Boston to Messrs. W & C Neil Merchants, Portsmouth, 1803 Jan 17 (Box 54, Folder 1049)
      - Van Staphorst & Co., Amsterdam, to Israel Thorndike, Beverly, Mass., 1803 May 26 (Box 54, Folder 1050)
      - White, John Campbell, Baltimore to William Neil, Portsmouth, New Hampshire, 1800 May 7 (Box 54, Folder 1051)
    - Miscellaneous Documents
      - Hartford, Connecticut. Two court documents completed in manuscript, 1785, 1798 (Box 54, Folder 1052)
      - York Factory in Ruperts Land, Hudson's Bay Company. Five shilling note, signed by H. Smith, Secretary and Wm. Williams, Governor, 1820 May 11 (Box 54, Folder 1053)
      - Portland, Oregon. Deed of lots of land in the city from George W. Higgins to Henry Sampson and Harley McDonald, 1852 Jun 7
      - Agent Lansdale, Wm. Craig & Antoni Plant. Copy of receipts for animals and public property, [1855] (Box 54, Folder 1054)
      - Wilkes, Charles. Recommendation for "Dr. Elliot." Holograph manuscript, 1864 Oct 22 (Box 54, Folder 1055)
      - Walla Walla, Washington. Ledger book page kept by a lumber hauler, 1868 Jun (Box 54, Folder 1056)
        Page clipped, obscuring text
      - Oregon Railway and Navigation Company receipt to D. J. Schwartzer for freight and charges from Astoria of a half barrel of claret, 188[-] Apr 3 (Box 54, Folder 1057)
      - "Fort Vancouver claim formerly James Douglas." Manuscript map, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1058)
    - Miscellaneous Writings
      - "Visit to Mount Rainier." Holograph and typescript of an article that appeared in The Columbian, Olympia, Puget Sound, Oregon, September 18, 1852 (Box 54, Folder 1059)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material
      - Congressional Record. "Alleged Bloody Oath of the Knights of Columbus. As reprinted from the Congressional Record, Feby. 15, 1913" (Box 54, Folder 1060)
      - The Young Men's Whig National Convention of Ratification. "Henry Clay, Our Nation's Statesman, And our Nation's Stay. Baltimore May 2d 1844." Silk bookmark (Box 54, Folder 1061)
      - [Idaho.] "Hurrah!! Washington, July 1, 1890: Idaho admitted. Forty four stars on the old flag." Small handbill, 1890 Jul 1 (Box 54, Folder 1062)
      - Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition. Invitation to opening, 1909 (Box 54, Folder 1063)
      - Fort Walla Walla reception invitation, 1886 (Box 54, Folder 1064)
      - Oregon Pioneer Association 24th Annual Reunion, Portland, Oregon. Invitation, 1896 (Box 54, Folder 1065)
      - Panama-Pacific International Exposition. Exhibitor's gift coupon for admission Nov. 2 1915 (Box 54, Folder 1066)
      - Fort Dalles Post Bakery. Printed bread ration cards, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1067)
      - Park Hotel, Livingston, Montana and Winters Park Hotel, Gardiner, Montana. Stationery envelopes (Box 54, Folder 1068)
      - Wells, Fargo & Co's Express shipping label, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1069)
      - The Wolf Creek Mining and Development Company share certificate (Box 54, Folder 1070)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Western
      - Atkinson, John. "C.S.N. Co's Steamer Capital Master." Photograph of an oil painting, 26.2 x 47 cm. on mount 40.4 x 56 cm., n.d.
        "To D. B. Foster, Portland, Oregon."
      - Eklund Studio. Three photographs of Charles Russell, visible image 23 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 1071)
      - Gardiner, R. H. "Ship Tillie E. Starbuck, Taking Pilot Off Point Lynas, Irish Channel." Photograph of an oil painting, 23.5 x 34 cm. on mount 35.2 x 42.9 cm., n.d.
        "R. H. Gardiner, Photo, Albina, Oregon"
        Stored in: Oversize box 63, folder 1193
      - Gillingham, Chas. L. "The [Autters?] and Pikes Peak Colorado Springs," 10.9 x 15.5 cm. on mount 11.2 x 17.7 cm. (Box 54, Folder 1072)
        Stamp of Chas. L. Gillingham, Colorado Springs, Colo. on verso
      - Scherer. "Confederate Ram Albemarle," 22 x 33.5 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1073)
        Signed by Gilbert Elliott, the builder. "Scherer, Photographer, St. Louis." With typescript note pasted on verso explaining provenance
      - Stormer, H. W. "Shoshone Spring, Manitou, Colorado," 10.7 x 16.5 cm. on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1074)
        No. 2002 in series Artistic Views of Colorado. Manitou - Saratoga of the West. With stamp of "W. I. Rudy & Co.'s Free Museum, Colo. Springs, Colo." on verso
      - Taber. [Cliff House, San Francisco], 14.8 x 23 cm. on mount 15.1 x 24.5 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1075)
      - Unidentified. [Photograph of a painting of Mount Hood?], 12 x 19 cm. on mount 13 x 21.4 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1076)
        "Pioneer Portrait and Landscape Photographic Studios. Jacksonville, Or. P. Britt & Son"
      - Unidentified. Photograph of Yankee Jim's, Placer County, California, in 1857, drawn from nature and lith. by Kuchel & Dresel, 13.6 x 24.5 cm.
      - Unidentified. Photoreproduction of drawings of Crow papooses, 34 x 41 cm. (irreg.), c.1909
        "To Mrs. Borghum [Borglum?] from J. H. Sharp, July 29 1909"
    - Other
      - Unidentified. "The Battle of Manila Bay, May 1st 1898." Photograph of a painting by an unidentified artist, 8 x 17.1 cm. on mount 13.7 x 21.6 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1077)
      - Unidentified. "A quiet ride in the country." Carte-de-visite photoreproduction of a drawing, 6.2 x 10 cm., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1078)
- Oversize, 17.92; (9 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from series I-VIII, and is organized in box order.
  - "Domes Yo Semite Cala." Watercolor, 29.9 x 45.3 cm. (in Series I), 1859 (Box 55, Folder 1079)
  - "Nevada Fall & Cañon. YoSemite - Cala." Watercolor, 30 x 45 cm. (in Series I), 1859 (Box 55, Folder 1080)
  - "New Astoria, Oregon." Pencil drawing, 18 x 53.9 cm. (in Series I), 1854 (Box 55, Folder 1081)
  - "Boundary between U.S. and B.C." Watercolor and pastel, 27.2 x 56.2 cm. (in Series I), 1860 (Box 55, Folder 1082)
  - "Looking up Kootenay River North of the 49th Parallel British Columbia." Watercolor, 30.5 x 45 cm. (in Series I), 1860 (Box 55, Folder 1083)
  - [Harbor scene.] Watercolor, 28.6 x 45.5 (in Series I) (Box 55, Folder 1084)
  - Hall, Bob. "F.E.R.A. Tannery Project. Butte, Montana." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 71 x 56 cm. (in Series III) (Box 55, Folder 1085)
  - Hall, Bob. "Old Time Cow Spread." Pen-and-ink drawing, 58.5 x 74 cm. (in Series III) (Box 55, Folder 1086)
  - Hall, Bob. [Two horses tied up in front of a blacksmith's.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 56 x 76 cm. (in Series III), 1954 (Box 55, Folder 1087)
  - Kehoe, Joseph W. [Lighthouse.] Watercolor, visible image 26 x 37 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1088)
  - Kehoe, Joseph W. [Man fishing near covered bridge, mountains in background.] Watercolor, visible image 33 x 43.5 cm. (in Series III) (Box 55, Folder 1089)
  - Kehoe, Joseph W. [Man fishing, two figures cleaning fish, at Celilo Falls?] Watercolor, 35.4 x 45 cm. (in Series III), 1955 (Box 55, Folder 1090)
  - Kehoe, Joseph W. [Winter Scene.] Watercolor, visible image 25.5 x 35.7 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1091)
  - Kleiber, Hans. "A Flock of Canvas backs in Flight." Watercolor, 41 x 32.5 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1092)
  - Kleiber, Hans. "A Log Boom -- Morning." Watercolor, 29.9 x 40.8 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1093)
  - Kleiber, Hans. "On the Clearwater River, Idaho." Watercolor, 27 x 37.2 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1094)
  - Kleiber, Hans. "Ranchester - Wyoming." Watercolor, 27 x 37.2 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1095)
  - Vernon I. Dorsey, San Francisco, Calif. to Richard B. Dorsey, Baltimore, Maryland (in Series I), 1851 Dec 15 (Box 56, Folder 1096)
  - Hall, Bob. Postcards (34 postcards of 23 images) (in Series III), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1097-1098)
  - Paxson, E. S. "Pap-oose." Pen-and-ink drawing in a small booklet with "Miss Dolly. A Merry Xmas -1903-" written on front, 12 x 6.2 cm. (in Series III) (Box 56, Folder 1099)
  - Paxson, E. S. "Phillippines 1908-9." Sketchbook containing eleven sketches in pencil, 14 x 22 cm. (in Series III), [1908-09] (Box 56, Folder 1100)
  - Agate, Alfred T. "Astoria." Steel engraving, 10 x 16 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1101)
  - Erb, I. J. Five postcards titled: "Antelope Feeding," "Chuck Wagon - The Cow Boys Restaurant," "The 'Dry Creek Stage' - Bill Fenton, Driver," "Spooked," "Whispering Winds." Lithographs (in Series IV) (Box 56, Folder 1102)
  - Proctor, Alexander Phimister. "Measurements of Mustangs made by A. Phimister Proctor, Kings Ranch - Texas, 1938-39." Sketchbook, 22.5 x 30.4 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 56, Folder 1103)
  - Postcards of Russell artwork. Color print (in Series IV), 1904-26, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1104-1106)
  - Postcards of Russell artwork. Print on silk (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1107)
  - "Bird's Eye View of Aberdeen, Wash." Collotype folding postcard, 9 x 27.8 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 56, Folder 1108)
  - "A Description of the City of Port Townsend, Jefferson County, State of Washington, U.S.A." Holograph and typescript, corrected (in Series II), 1891 (Box 57, Folder 1109)
  - "The Surf Smelt of the Northwest Coast and method of taking them by the Quillehute Indians, West Coast of Washington Territory." Holograph (in Series II), 1879 (Box 57, Folder 1110)
  - "Synopsis of a report of work done in the Queen Charlotte Islands British Columbia, during the summer of 1883, under instructions from Professor Spencer F. Baird." Holograph (in Series II), 1884 Jan 16 (Box 57, Folder 1111)
  - "Ascent of Mount Rainier," The Daily Tribune, Olympia (in Series II), 1870 Aug 29 (Box 57, Folder 1112)
  - "Frontier Life in Washington Territory." Four wood engravings featured in Harper's Weekly (in Series II), 1857 Aug 22 (Box 57, Folder 1113)
  - Office and staff of the Pacific Monthly, 18.5 x 24.2 cm. on mount 27.2 x 34.6 cm. (in Series III) (Box 57, Folder 1114)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "The Forestry Building." Pen-and-ink, watercolor and gouache, 25.5 x 35.5 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1115)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Pioneer P.O." Charcoal and gouache, 24.1 x 29 cm. on sheet 32 x 34.4 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1116)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Steel bridge." Pastel, 31.4 x 22.4 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1117)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Timberline Lodge - Front view." Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 26 x 36.6 cm. on sheet 38.2 x 47.8 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1118)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. [Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo.] Watercolor, 50 x 37.6 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1119)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Building the Morning Star." Etching, plate mark 24 x 35.9 cm. on sheet 32.1 x 44.6 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1120)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Building the Star of Oregon - 1841." Offset lithograph, 34.9 x 47.8 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1121)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Burnside Bridge." Etching, plate mark 35.9 x 20.9 cm. on sheet 41.5 x 27.6 cm. (in Series III), 1932 (Box 58, Folder 1122)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Burnside Bridge Tower." Etching, plate mark 35.7 x 20.8 cm. on sheet 40.1 x 26.9 cm. (in Series III), 1932 (Box 58, Folder 1123)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Ruins of the State House." Etching, plate mark 27.3 x 18.5 cm. on sheet 36 x 25.4 cm. (in Series III), 1936 (Box 58, Folder 1124)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Timberline Lodge, Mt. Hood, Oregon." Lithograph of an etching, visible image 25 x 32 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1125)
  - McIlwraith, William Forsyth. "Timberline Lodge with Skiers - View from left end." Etching, plate mark 23.5 x 36 cm. on sheet 33 x 45.8 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1126)
  - Pease, Lute. "Judgment of Solomon Wilson." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 60.8 x 45.5 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1127)
  - Pease, Lute. "Neptune to Frightfulness." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 61 x 48.5 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1128)
  - Pease, Lute. "Seventh Annual Rose Festival. Portland Oregon June 9 to 14 1913. Low Rates On All Lines." Color print poster, 69 x 53 cm. (in Series III) (Box 58, Folder 1129)
  - Augier, S. "Across the Continent. Westward the Course of Empire Takes its Way." Colored etching, 34 x 43.9 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 58, Folder 1130)
  - Augier, S. "The Rocky Mountains." Colored etching, plate mark 33.6 x 43.9 cm. on sheet 52 x 65.2 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1131)
  - Baillie, James. "The Great Fight, between Tom Hyer & Yankee Sullivan, for $10,000." Chromolithograph, 34.7 x 49.8 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1132)
  - Currier & Ives. "The Hunters Shanty In the Adirondacks." Tinted lithograph, 46.4 x 60.7 cm. (in Series IV), 1861 (Box 58, Folder 1133)
  - Davenport, Homer. "I gave him a slice of bread now he's happy." Pen-and-ink drawing, 72.3 x 57 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1134)
  - Davenport, Homer. [Man, "Beef Trust" injecting "Poison" into cow, with a graveyard in background, graves marked "U.S.V."] Pen-and-ink drawing, 72.5 x 57 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1135)
  - Davenport, Homer. "The Snake is Fairer Than the Whiskey As He Rattles Before He Takes Your Life." Pen-and-ink drawing, 57.2 x 72.3 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1136)
  - Davenport, Homer. "'Substitution', or What's the difference." Pen-and-ink drawing with typescript captions pasted on, some partially missing, 72.5 x 57 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1137)
  - Farnham, A. M. [California mission.] Lithograph, 36 x 48 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1138)
  - Flagg, James Montgomery. "'Come, let's make the best of it & cheat the gossip." Pen-and-ink drawing, 54.7 x 75 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1139)
  - Fries, Albert. "The U.S. Ship 'New York.'" Lithograph, 24.5 x 60.1 cm. (in Series IV), 1895 (Box 59, Folder 1140)